Dr. Khalifa: أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
[45:33] The evils of their works will become obvious to them, and the very things they mocked will come back and haunt them.
[45:34] It will be proclaimed: "Today we forget you, just as you forgot the meeting of this day. Your abode is the hellfire, and you will have no helpers.
[45:35] "This is because you mocked and ridiculed GOD's revelations, and were preoccupied with the first life." Consequently, they will never exit therefrom, nor will they be excused.
[45:36] To GOD belongs all praise; Lord of the heavens, Lord of the earth, Lord of the universe.
[45:37] To Him belongs all supremacy in the heavens and the earth. He is the Almighty, Most Wise.
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful. [46:1] H. M. [46:2] The revelation of this scripture is from GOD, the Almighty, the Wise.
[46:3] We did not create the heavens and the earth, and everything between them except for a specific purpose, and for a finite interim. Those who disbelieve are totally oblivious to the warnings.
[46:4] Say, "Consider the idols you have set up beside GOD. Show me what on earth did they create. Do they own part of the heavens? Show me any other scripture or any piece of knowledge that supports your idolatry, if you are truthful."
The Idols Totally Unaware
[46:5] Who is farther astray than those who idolize beside GOD idols that can never respond to them until the Day of Resurrection, and are totally unaware of their worship?
This is what most Sunnis and Shias do.
The next page,
The Idols Disown Their Worshipers*
[46:6] And when the people are summoned (on the Day of Judgment), their idols will become their enemies, and will denounce their idolatry.*
[46:7] When our revelations were recited to them, clearly, those who disbelieved said of the truth that came to them, "This is obviously magic!"
So, we're talking about idol worshipers who idolize people.
Because we're told in verse 6,
[46:6] ...when the people are summoned (on the Day of Judgment), their idols will become their enemies, and will denounce their idolatry.*
So, Ali will have to denounce all the Shias, and Muhammad denounces all the Muslims.
Dr. Khalifa: In fact, this is documented in the Quran.
A man: There's (unintelligible) Muslims.
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
A man: There's (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: And their idols can never respond to them until the Day of Resurrection.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And Muhammad and Ali and Hussein cannot respond to anybody.
A woman: Until the Day of Resurrection. Then, they will be disown them.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, they disown them. Right.
They never knew about you.
Now, these people, these particular people, [46:7] When our revelations were recited to them, clearly,...
that is worship God alone, uphold the word of God alone, the creed is La Elaha Ella Allah,
[46:7] ...those who disbelieved say to the truth that comes to them, "This is obviously magic!"
[46:8] When they say, "He fabricated this," say, "If I fabricated this, then you cannot protect me from GOD. He is fully aware of everything you scheme. He suffices as a witness between me and you. He is the Forgiver, Most Merciful."
When I apply this to me personally, I notice always when it says "say", it is already said.
I always tell them "if I'm a liar, then this is my problem. What is the message? What am I telling you? I'm telling you, worship God alone, and uphold the word of God alone.
If I'm lying to you, this is my problem, as far as you're concerned. You can benefit from the truth, if it is truthful, and you can benefit from the message. If I am a liar, it's my problem, not yours."
[46:9] Say, "I am not different from other messengers. I have no idea what will happen to me or to you. I only follow what is revealed to me. I am no more than a profound warner."
[46:10] Say, "What if it is from GOD and you disbelieved in it? A witness from the Children of Israel has borne witness to a similar phenomenon,*...
So, look at the footnote here.
*46:10 This witness is Rabbi Judah the Pious (11th Century A.D.), who discovered the same 19-based mathematical code in intact fragments of the scripture (see Appendix 1).
So, obviously, number 9, "say" here, refers to our generation.
[46:9] ..."I am not different from other messengers. I have no idea what will happen to me or to you. I only follow what is revealed to me. I am no more than a profound warner."
[46:10] Say, "What if it is from GOD and you disbelieved in it? A witness from the Children of Israel has borne witness to a similar phenomenon,* and he has believed, while you have turned arrogant. Surely, GOD does not guide the wicked people."
Rabbi Judah the Pious is undoubtedly a believer when you read his writings.
God alone, in fact, he's a strict scripturist, just like we are.
Number 11,
[46:11] Those who disbelieved said about those who believed, "If it were anything good, they would not have preceded us to it." Because they were not guided thereby, they said, "This is an old fabrication!"
Number 12,
[46:12] Before this, the book of Moses provided guidance and mercy. And this is a confirming Arabic scripture to warn those who transgressed, and to give good news to the righteous.
Good News
[46:13] Surely, those who said, "Our Lord is GOD," then led a righteous life, will have no fear, nor will they grieve.
Sounds familiar?
Number 14,
[46:14] They have deserved Paradise, where they abide forever; a reward for their works.
Congratulations.
Any questions?
Parivash: Yes. That is Sura... Those who are Christians, not here, but those who not fear, (unintelligible). The question was
those who are Jewish or Christians, no fear.
How about the people who do not believe you are messenger?
Dr. Khalifa: Say "they're going to Hell."
Parivash: Ok. They say "how about this?"
Dr. Khalifa: Say... Parivash: I told them something.
Parivash: I said "this is for people who didn't reach the truth." Dr. Khalifa: who don't know. Yeah.
Parivash: If you, if you show...
Dr. Khalifa: If these people, if they come and see the proof, I give them the proof, I give them the message, And they say, and they don't believe, they're go to hell. Parivash: Ok. Yes. And they, they go. Yeah. Yeah.
Parivash: I, I... Dr. Khalifa: If they are believers who are included here, they readily accept everything.
Parivash: Yes.
Parivash: I said "for the person of belief, now is the time after Moses."
And everybody, you know, they don't know and they die or they all, they all Heaven.
Parivash: But if you did show them the truth, and they still, they say "no, we don't believe." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They go to Hell.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. This is for people who don't know.
They're in the middle of the jungle. They don't know anything about Quran or anything...
But anytime you show them the Quran, they'll believe it.
They find nothing objectionable in it.
You show them any proof from God, they accept it.
You see, God will guide them and make them... I mean...
Parivash: And after this, Alhamdu Lillah, they say "yeah, yeah, this makes sense."
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A man: Would it be appropriate if somebody, regarding verse 10, [46:10] ...A witness from the Children of Israel has borne witness to a similar phenomenon,...
A man: If people say "well, it also means that this verse also, a part of the verse also refers to Jesus",
A man: I would say "yes, it used to refer vis-à-vis Muhammad, but now it refers to vis-à-vis, Rashad." Dr. Khalifa: No, actually...
Dr. Khalifa: No, it never refers to Jesus.
No, Jesus is not considered one of the children of Israel in the Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: He's considered the vanguard of a new movement and a whole new religion.
A man: In the Quran, it says this? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: (46:10) وَشَهِدَ شَاهِدٌۭ مِّنۢ بَنِىٓ إِسْرَٰٓءِيلَ
You know, if it was Jesus, God would have said "Jesus borne witness."
He wouldn't call Jesus one of the children of Israel.
A man: There has no...
I mean, there are two possibilities. One is that the verse had a particular relevance at the time of Muhammad
and it has a further deeper relevance at your time.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A man: But not this one.
Dr. Khalifa: It's just one of the things that were to come later, to become obvious later.
A witness from among the children of Israel borne witness to something like it.
But Jesus didn't bear witness to something like the Quran. It's totally different.
This is...There's no question that it is Rabbi Judah the Pious.
A man: And he has believed. Dr. Khalifa: And... Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok...
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
It was an excellent brief presentation of the perpetual miracle that God sent to us.
That is to be witnessed by anybody, in any place, at any time.
Anybody in Tokyo, Japan, can open this and witness the miracle.
This mathematically coded book. This is an original idea.
And I have to take you back a few years, a few centuries actually, where the realization came first that God spoke to us in mathematics.
It was about 900 years ago when a Jewish Rabbi discovered this number 19 in the intact remnants of the scriptures.
Specifically in the prayers that were given to them through Abraham, from prophet Abraham,
just like our Namaz came through Abraham.
What happened about 900 years ago was that the Jews in France added a short statement
to their morning prayer, which was "blessed are those who follow the righteous path."
They just added this harmless, seemingly harmless statement.
Rabbi Judah the Pious, who was living at that time, just wrote a barrage of literature,
eight huge volumes, as to why this short statement would destroy what he called Divine rhythm,
or the key that causes contact between us and God.
And he showed that the number 19 is the basis of the scriptures.
The language of God is speaking to us, that it is the key to the Word of God. And I have it reproduced here, in the appendix.
Actually, Rabbi Judah the Pious, I think some of you know this, is actually mentioned in the Quran, in Sura 46, verse 10.
I reproduced part of his writing about this, on page 636 of this book.
Now, I'm quoting from a book entitled "Studies in Jewish Mysticism."
It says "the people, Jews in France, made it a custom to add in the morning prayer,
"the words, Ashrei temimei derekh, which means, blessed are those who walk the righteous way.
"And our Rabbi the Pious, of blessed memory, wrote that they were completely and utterly wrong.
"It is all gross falsehood, because there are only 19 times" Now notice the number 19.
"There are only 19 times that the Holy Name is mentioned, in that portion of the morning prayer.
"And similarly, you find the word Elohim, which means God, 19 times, in the pericope of the Ve-’elleh shemot.
"Similarly, you find that Israel were called sons 19 times, and there are many other examples."
Now, listen to this. "All these sets of 19 are intricately intertwined, and they contain many secrets and esoteric meanings,
"which are contained in more than 8 large volumes.
"Furthermore, in this section, there are 152 words", that's 19 times 8.
In 46:10
It's 46:10 or 42:10.
Let me see.
Maybe 42:10.
It's not 46:10.
Yes, yes.
46:10 says
[46:10] Say, "What if it is from GOD...
the Quran
[46:10] ..."What if it is from GOD and you disbelieved in it? A witness from the Children of Israel has borne witness to a similar phenomenon,*...
And I believe that this verse refers to Rabbi Judah the Pious, because if you read his writing, he's really a believer.
So, what I would like to say is that the number 19 has been always the key...
has always been the key in God's writings.
And one of the strange statements of Galileo was that "mathematics is the language with which God created the universe."
That was a statement by Galileo.
And we come to realize now that in nature, the number 19 also, which may be God's signature, is evident in God's creation.
The sun, the moon, and the earth line up in the same position every 19 years.
And you can see this in detail again if you go to the library and look at the Jewish calendar,
in the Jewish encyclopedia, under calendar, you will see this, because they have to adjust the calendar once every 19 years.
The human body has 209 bones, which is 19 times 11.
The human fetus, it is now established that the human, a full term embryo, is in the mother's womb 266 days, 19 times 14.
And this is not 267.
And you'll see this in the textbooks in medical schools.
So, obviously God puts His stamp on everything, including the Quran.
The Quran is the only scripture that is intact.
And this is where we have the system intact. This...
As Behrouz shared with you some of these phenomena.
Maybe you can, if you sit over there, you can see.
Just these numbers here will convince anybody that this is not a human-made book.
This top number, I'm gonna repeat because Behrouz went through it a little bit too fast.
This number here is the number of digits.
If you write every verse in the Quran, the number of every verse. For example, the first Sura is 7 verses.
So, you write 1234567.
Next Sura is 286 verses. So, you write next to that, 1234, all the way through 286.
And so on, all the way to the end of the Quran.
So, we're talking about the physical structure of this book.
That's every verse in the Quran. You just write the number. You end up with a long number, which we have hanging on the wall at Masjid Tucson.
And the number of digits is 12,692. This number is a multiple of 19.
This is the number of digits in the long number, which takes about three pages, printed by the computer.
And the long number itself is also a multiple of 19.
So, this confirms the physical structure of the book,
how many Suras and how many verses in every Sura.
This number here is the number of verses in the Quran.
Right. You just look at this book and take the first Sura, 7 verses, second Sura, 286 verses, third Sura, 200 verses.
You add these numbers, you come up with this number, 6346, which is also a multiple of 19.
The number of Suras, of course, is 114, which is 19 times 6.
The first verse, which is very famous, Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem (بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيْمِ) is 19 letters.
Okay, 2698, this is the number of the word "God" in the Quran, the word "Allah" from the beginning to the end, 2698.
A multiple of 19.
And considering how the Quran was revealed to the Prophet Muhammad, separated in time and place,
it is really incredible. In fact, when we were working on this book, we had about 6 college graduates, including 1 Ph.D.
And we had so much difficulty just keeping track of the word God. We made so many mistakes in doing this.
And...
The book, of course, confirms itself, because if you know this, if you open this book,
any of you who has it, you'll see in English on any page, you'll see in English that the word "GOD" is written in capital bold letters.
So, anyone can easily verify this. And the number of these, the word God is down written on every page.
So, you can look at any page and confirm that it is 6 times. This page here, page 97, has 6 words "Allah" in it.
You can do this randomly on any page and make sure that these counts are correct.
And you go to the end of the book and you see that the word "God" is a multiple of 19, 2698.
19 times 142.
This number here is the sum of all the numbers mentioned in the Quran, without repetition.
There are 30 numbers mentioned in the Quran. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 19,
20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 80, 99, 100, 200, 300, 400, 500, 600, 700, not 700, 500, 3,000, 5,000, 50,000, 100,000.
And you add them up, you get this total. 162,146, which is a multiple of 19.
Now, you notice these are physical facts.
Nobody is saying "in my opinion, the total of the numbers in the Quran is 162,140." It's a physical fact. Yes sir?
A man: Is Quran has only one version, or I mean, different versions of Quran?
Dr. Khalifa: No, it's only one version.
A man: One version.
A man: There hasn't been any contest as to the different, any, no denomination.
Dr. Khalifa: No. There's only one Quran.
Dr. Khalifa: There's one Quran.
A man: Yes. Just like in Christianity, that the...
Dr. Khalifa: There are different versions of the Bible.
A man: The Bible has different versions (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: There's King James Version. There is Martin Luther Version and so on.
Dr. Khalifa: But the Quran is only one version. There are no differences. A man: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is a physical fact.
It is nobody's opinion.
And it's... all you need to do is find the numbers in the Quran and add them up. If they don't add up to a multiple of 19, then the whole thing collapses. The subject is over.
But this has been in existence for 20 years now, and it's been scrutinized.
This research has been scrutinized more than any research in the history of humanity.
Because back home, they looked at all these numbers, trying to find any errors.
It's been confirmed and reconfirmed that these are physical facts.
This number here is the total of the verses wherever the word "God" is mentioned.
The word "Allah" is mentioned. And this is really and truly awesome.
Because, again, if you have a copy of this, just open it at random anywhere, and see the word "God."
Okay, I opened at page 259. So, open page 259 if you have this, and I can tell you what's in it.
In page 259, you see verses 25 to 33 in Sura 14.
And you noticed that the word God, Allah, is mentioned in verse 25.
Verse 27 has 3 of them. Verse 26 has 0. Verse 28 has 1. 29 has 0. 30 has 1 word "Allah."
31 has 0, and 32 has 1, and 33 has 0.
So in this, there are 3 words "Allah" in verse 27, but we only add 27.
Verse 27. So, we add 25 plus 27 plus 28 plus 30 plus 32.
We add only the verses wherever the word "Allah" is mentioned, whether it is 1 time or 10 times.
And this is the total, in the whole Quran.
It is 118123, which is also a multiple of 19.
So, all these phenomena defy coincidence, or defy human manufacture.
And we immediately realize that we have in our hands God's message to you.
You have full confidence, because this is the age of computers.
People have been demanding tangible evidence. Now, we have tangible evidence,
that this is God speaking to us, and not any human being trying to fool us.
Ok, now that the book is proven by physical evidence, we have confidence that this is God speaking to us.
It is not any human being with the shortcomings of human beings.
And in the book, we have answers to these questions.
And we know that God is speaking to us. God is telling us.
He created us, and He's telling us where we came from. He's telling us why we are here on this earth.
And He's telling us where we go from here.
And, and like the Quran says, it says, none can tell you this like The Expert, one of the names of God, Khabir (خبیر).
In Arabic, (35:14) وَلَا يُنَبِّئُكَ مِثْلُ خَبِيرٍۢ None can tell you these things like The Expert.
God is The Supreme Expert.
So now, I will try to share with you what God tells us about these questions.
Where did you come from?
Do you have some markers?
Oh yes, thank you.
Ok, why are we searching for these questions?
Where did we come from?
It's... We learn from Quran that we are here. We have no recollection of our previous past.
But we were all in God's kingdom. You can think of us as angels. We used to be angels, in God's kingdom.
So, if I draw a line representing all the creatures in God's kingdom, billions of years ago.
And this includes you and me. Billions of years ago. It's just very clear in the Quran that we existed in the past.
For example, in Sura 7, verse 143, God says "I gathered all of you, all the descendants of Adam, and I had you bear witness that I alone am your Lord."
God tells us that.
But we don't have any recollection of this. We don't remember standing before God and saying "we bear witness You are our Lord."
So, the Quran teaches us we don't have any remembrance of that. And this is one of the purposes of us being here.
It's to come into an existence where we do not remember the past, and start, have a fresh start.
Then, we are given two messages, one message from God, and one message from Satan.
And we are supposed to freely make a choice.
God gave us the freedom to choose. You can choose either one of them, either God's message, or Satan's message.
As you know, I'm gonna interrupt a bit in the, what God is telling us in the middle of the subject.
In the middle of the subject, Adam and Eve were in Heaven.
And God gave them a message. This is because all of us, I'm sure, know this.
But God gave Adam and Eve a message. He said "you're in Paradise. You can enjoy anything you want, but not this tree."
"Don't come close to this tree."
That was God's message to Adam and Eve.
And they stayed in Heaven, God knows how long, maybe thousands, maybe millions of years.
So, but the point is, for as long as they respected God's commandment, God's law, they stayed there.
And then, most of you know, Satan went to them and said "eat from this tree."
Ok. So now, they have two messages.
(unintelligible), how are you?
Adam and Eve were in Heaven, or in Paradise, or Heaven, the same thing.
And they had a message from God telling them "do not eat from this tree."
And they had a message from Satan saying "eat from this tree."
For as long as they obeyed, adhered by God's message, they stayed in Heaven.
Once they listened to Satan, they were kicked out of Heaven.
And this is what brought us here.
I mean, as a second coming to this world, not the initial. This is not the original sin.
Eating from the tree is not the original sin as believed in the previous scriptures.
So, this line is representing all of God's creatures, including you and me.
And these creatures of God have different responsibilities, different assignments or work.
And depending on their duties, they have different powers.
For example, if somebody assigns to you something to do in New York, your company says "you must go to New York and do something and come back."
They'll give you a ticket to get on a plane, fly to New York, do a job and come back.
This is some power given to you.
So, God's creatures have different powers. One of the most powerful creatures, not the most powerful creature, one of the powerful creatures,
now we got to know as Satan, his God-given powers went to his head.
He had an egotistic problem. He thought he can be a god besides God.
He thought he can run a dominion besides God.
And this immediately created various degrees of agreement or disagreement with Satan.
So, let's... just to put the matter in perspective, we're going to put a representation of how many creatures agreed with Satan.
The vast majority of God's creatures did not agree with Satan, only a few. I'm gonna represent them by this red bar.
I hope you can see it right there.
So, the vast majority of creatures, they said "no way, Satan cannot be a god besides God. Only God can be a god."
I mean, this is from a practical point of view.
There's simply more to God-hood than Satan thought.
And this is reflected in this world now, that Satan cannot run the world.
There are many starving children, many diseases, earthquakes, cancer.
All this is Satan's incompetence, reflects Satan's incompetence in this world.
These creatures that did not agree with Satan are the angels.
They....They are now, the creatures became classified.
The creatures who upheld God's absolute authority were classified as angels.
The creatures that rebelled and agreed with Satan were classified as, and then further classified. Let's now classify them as rebels.
They did not believe in God's absolute authority.
Now, I'm going to take this little dot here.
By the way, this little dot represents something like a trillion creatures.
The number of God's angels is not known to anybody except God.
You see this in the Quran, in Sura 74, verse 31, where God says "only God knows the number of the angels."
Even the angels don't know how many of them there are.
As you see, this red dot represents a trillion creatures.
And the blue line is much larger. So, there's countless numbers of angels.
I'm going to extend this dot here into a long line.
We're still dealing with the question, where did we come from?
This line represents about a trillion creatures.
They are the creatures that agreed with Satan.
And this includes you and me, on this line, to different degrees.
Let's say here are the least agreeable with Satan, and these are the most (unintelligible) agreeing with Satan.
God gave these creatures a second chance. First of all, the angels said "since these creatures here rebelled, put them all in Hell."
"Throw them all in Hell. Banish them from Your kingdom."
And in Sura 2, verse 30, God says "No."
One of the names of God is the Most Merciful.
God wanted to give us another chance to reconsider our decision to side with Satan.
In Sura 2, verse 30, God says "I know what you do not know."
The angels said "throw them all in Hell."
And God said "I know what you do not know."
What did God know that the angels didn't know?
God knew that some of us, deep in our hearts, believe in God's absolute authority.
But for some reason, we were swept in the crowd, and we agreed with Satan to different degrees.
So... Pardon?
So, this line here, representing the rebels, God gave them a second chance.
He said "how would you like to reconsider your agreement with Satan?
(unintelligible). Mã Shã Allãh.
Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: She wrote me a fantastic letter. She's early, very early believer. It takes a lot of courage to do that.
A woman: I'm proceeding in 70.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: Why should we not have a messenger?
A woman: I mean, I didn't distinguish between a messenger or prophet, whatever I said.
But I said "this is the time we need someone when
God (unintelligible) in the Quran says, we have sent messengers for who went astray. And there were two at a time, many times.
But I said "in this time, when amongst the most chosen people, the Muslims, which had the last prophet, and things finalized and...
why even these people are going astray. We are going astray, like we know the wrong things that we are not supposed to do.
A woman: All the Muslim countries are at war with each other.
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A woman: Why don't He, why don't He help us now? He won't forsake us, I was so sure.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: I said "He has to send somebody.
A woman: (unintelligible).
A woman: (unintelligible) I said "I don't see why not." I would accept him,
A woman: if somebody showed up and said "I'm from God."
Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A woman: As long as he's reading the Word of God I said... Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. By the way, she's reading her letters.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, I went in there to look for her letter, which I know I have it somewhere, but I couldn't find it.
What she just said now is exactly her letters.
But she added to it that, "but to have the messenger come in my lifetime, this is a dream that I never expected."
A woman: Immediately I said it, and then I said "oh, I may not be so lucky. I'm...
And if he really comes, will I have the courage to stand up and say "oh, I accept somebody there. He won't be right in front of me. (unintelligible)." Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the letter, exactly. This is what she wrote.
Can you imagine? And this is very early, when nobody else had any courage, you know, to...
Because it was very difficult, even on me, you know, initially.
A woman: Something else is...
Dr. Khalifa: So, is it an honor or not to know Mrs. Amir Ali?
Mã Shã Allãh. She's very special. Mã Shã Allãh.
A woman: Something else is really flying to my head. I was doing it like three weeks ago.
(unintelligible) In my life, I had people who really played for, I don't know if they were (unintelligible) or not, but
when you see them, you felt they are.
But what we did was, we just went to their houses, and we just expected them, or stayed with them for half an hour,
or maybe just played the period we were there.
But (Unintelligible)
And we were hoping that they will, like, help us or give us a spray, lighting.
And then I, you know, I compared that with what I have here.
I felt, like, completely different.
You see, like, over there, we went and we saw "oh, like, (unintelligible)",
and we made a person, you know, into a sacred.
And we just "oh, (unintelligible)."
You know, go and get something else from them.
I think at this time, we have lots of people like that.
You know, they might agree, but the way that you see, like, we will be preached (unintelligible).
I mentioned to the group, I said "Alhamdu Lillah, we might play (unintelligible), rather than just leaving it at that. (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, Alhamdu Lillah. We're very special. Very special.
So, the things that, what is happening now is, first of all,
give us a chance to finish the work that needs to be finished. Second is to select these very special people.
(56:10) ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ The elite of the elite.
There are people who are joining, and sometimes you think, if the opening up happened, like, last year,
look how many people would have been deprived of this position, of being elite of the elite.
Look, there's elite of the elite or (56:10) ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ ٱلسَّـٰبِقُونَ are the people who are in the
vanguards of the movement, at the time when it is being persecuted, and everybody is calling us stupid, and
way off, and all the crazy, and all these names.
You know, these are the...
But the new generations don't deserve half the credit.
I always use the example of the Kuleyni's kids.
Farima and... Farima and Amir. Farima is a believer, Mã Shã Allãh.
And she is... she went through, she's an adult, who made that very crucial decision.
When I stayed at their house, and then, after a couple of days, the neighborhood kids come and say "where is God's messenger? We wanna see God's messenger."
Because their kids are saying "Guess, who's sleeping in our house?"
So, those kids, they grow up with this belief, so they don't, I mean, they have a fantastic credit,
but it's not half as, not one millionth of the credit that the adults get.
So during this period, God has selected these special people.
Alhamdu Lillah.
I'm glad this 33:7 came along.
Well, this is enough of the load for the morning. So, congratulations.
The floor is open to general discussions.
A man: Can I ask one more question?
Dr. Khalifa: Sure. A man: How do you explain to people, for example, the story of Shaykh Uthman, I don't know, are you familiar with him or not?
A man: I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, oh,...
Dr. Khalifa: إزيّك؟ کیف حالک؟ in Arabic.
Dr. Khalifa: What is the connection? إزيّك؟ and کیف حالک؟
This is Egyptian (إزيّك؟) and this is Arabic (کیف حالک؟)
When you think about... Look at this. Did you hear?
Dr. Khalifa: I'm sure he knows what he's saying.
A woman: Yeah, sometimes (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Translate.
Dr. Khalifa: Just when you think about it, it really is a proof of God's existence.
A woman: You know, and God designed our brains and, you know certain way we learn the languages and our (unintelligible) and the way we process.
Dr. Khalifa: As a matter of fact, language is the only thing that distinguishes the human being in the animal kingdom.
The closest creature to us, the chimps, or the orangutans. How come they don't speak?
They don't. Yeah.
Behrouz: Is it like they were talking to animals?
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Edip: They have, I think, a different kind of communication. Dr. Khalifa: Oh yeah, oh yeah, definitely. But I'm talking about the sound.
Edip: And it's perfect. (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The language of the bees. I was talking to Sammy today about the language of the bees.
Edip: (unintelligible) Yes. by then. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: Subhan Allah.
Dr. Khalifa: I only mention it because I studied it.
I know how to speak bees bees.
Like Chinese, English, Japanese, and bee bees.
The scouts, the bee scouts, will go and come back and tell the workers in the hive to travel five miles northeast, 45 degrees.
Yes, and they'll go exactly to that location where the food is, or the flowers are.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: They started... Pardon?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, any day. On any day.
They don't go by the sun, no.
Yes.
That's what God taught them. But they did this by marking, they're putting colored dots on the scouts and the workers, different colors.
And they watch them, and then the scouts will go and they'll come back and they do certain things.
And it's the language of the bees.
A woman: Muhammad (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yeah? Muhammad?
God puts the variations in the languages as the sign that comes after the creation of the heavens and the earth.
This tells us how important it is.
And the change in our colors.
Number 23 says,
[30:23] Among His signs is your sleeping during the night or the day, and your working in pursuit of His bounties. In this, there are sufficient proofs for people who hear.
Only yesterday, I heard on the radio that sleeping is one thing that's still mysterious to the scientists.
They don't know why we need sleep and what happens that refreshes, changes a person who sleeps dead, like myself, at about 8:30, into a person who is alert.
What is it that happens in sleeping? Why do we sleep? They don't know.
I mean, this is the last decade of the 20th century and the scientists do not know why we sleep, what the mechanism is or what happens.
[30:23] Among His signs is your sleeping during the night or the day, and your working in pursuit of His bounties. In this, there are sufficient proofs for people who hear.
[30:24] Among His signs is that He shows you the lightning as a source of fear, as well as hope, and He sends down from the sky water to revive a land that died. In these, there are sufficient proofs for people who understand.
Rain.
Rain is just the sign of God.
Can you imagine if we send astronauts in a spaceship and give them a system where the water circulates?
The three astronauts in a spaceship and the water evaporates, makes a cloud around the spaceship, goes with the spaceship where it goes.
And then rains on them fresh water. Perfect.
I mean, how will you, how are we gonna do this system? God did it on the spaceship Earth.
A renewable source of fresh water.
We have to think.
This is why God uses the word "think" a lot in the Quran.
See at the end of verse 21?
These are signs or sufficient proofs for people who think.
If there is no rain on Earth for one year, everybody will die. This will tell you how important it is.
If there is no rain for one year on Earth, everybody will die.
So, that's among His signs.
25.
[30:25] Among His signs is that the heaven and the earth are standing at His disposal. Finally, He calls you out of the earth, one call, whereupon you immediately rise.
After telling us all these signs, do we have any doubt that God will resurrect the dead?
No doubt.
26,
[30:26] To Him belongs everyone in the heavens and the earth; all are subservient to Him.
[30:27] And He is the One who initiates the creation, then repeats it; this is the easiest thing for Him...
Now "repeats", it can refer to resurrection, the second Hereafter.
Or it can mean that Rachel is a repetition of Batool.
Batool all over again.
[30:27] ...He is the One who initiates the creation, then repeats it; this is the easiest thing for Him. And to Him belongs the most sublime similitude, in the heavens and the earth. He is the Almighty, Most Wise.
Absurdity of Idolatry
[30:28] He cites for you herein an example from among yourselves: Do you ever elevate your servants or subordinates to the level where they rival you, and to the point that you pay them as much allegiance and respect as is being paid to you? We thus explain the revelations for the people who understand.
God is the Creator of all things.
And He is the boss of the universe. Will He elevate anybody to the status of a god?
I mean, if you don't accept this for yourself, why should you attribute it to God?
Therefore, idolatry is absurd.
[30:29] Indeed, the transgressors have followed their own opinions, without knowledge. Thus, who can guide those who have been sent astray by GOD? No one can help them.
And verse 30 tells us that monotheism, worshipping God alone, is a natural instinct in all of us.
[30:30] Therefore, you shall devote yourself to the religion of strict monotheism. Such is the natural instinct placed into the people by GOD. Such creation of GOD will never change. This is the perfect religion, but most people do not know.
It's a natural instinct.
We are born with the knowledge that we must worship God alone.
Then, God puts in your body a devil to tell you "no, don't do that."
"You must believe in Hussein, and Ali, and Muhammad, and Jesus, and Mary and Saint Francis.
Edip: Here's the nature, Ok, this is the natural instinct placed into the people by God. Such creation of God will never change.
Edip: In other words, with idol worship, they want to change the creation of God.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: I have trouble with the understanding of this verse. But from here, the creation of, God created us to believe.
Dr. Khalifa: No, This means that the babies that will be born in the next 10 years, 100 years, to the end of the world, will have the same knowledge.
So, it will never change. This fact will never change.
Because obviously, the vast majority of people do change.
Edip: But they change by taking, by following the (unintelligible), they change the nature for God. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: But this verse says it will never change.
So, God is talking about the babies that will be born in the future.
(30:30) فِطْرَتَ ٱللَّهِ ٱلَّتِى فَطَرَ ٱلنَّاسَ عَلَيْهَا ۚ لَا تَبْدِيلَ لِخَلْقِ ٱللَّهِ
Edip: But they grow and they can change.
Dr. Khalifa: How... Isn't it in every page of the Quran it says, devote yourself to God alone?
What's wrong with the people? Why do they have to stick Muhammad and Jesus with God? Why?
And they turn down right hostile when we tell them what God is saying.
Of course, we know why, but it just never ceases to amaze us.
Every page of the Quran says "God alone, devote yourself to God alone. God is the One who created you. God is the One who has the power.
"Nobody else has power. They're all dead. They're powerless." Every page.
A woman: Not even the ones who would read the Quran (unintelligible) that is they don't know (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. A woman: And they said "we shouldn't read the Quran with meaning. It's wrong. We're not supposed to. When it's translated, the meaning can be different."
A woman: "It can be very different."
But you cannot probably have the exact meaning in Arabic.
A woman: But you can take up two, three different translations and see. And then, Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A woman: coincidentally, if a woman asked me for anything, she had used an English translation from our house.
She wanted to find out where it was. And then I picked up this translation. And I showed her. And she read the verse and I read the verse.
A woman: And I said "see, the words are so different. And they've been printed years the past. But the meaning is the same." Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A woman: "So, why don't you read?" She said "oh, but we're not allowed to."
A woman: You see, their heads, or their minds tells them "don't read the meaning, you'll be understanding it wrongly." Dr. Khalifa: Satan. This is what Satan tells them. Yes.
A woman: So, they are afraid to read them.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A woman: I said "you're already missing it. And you don't know what you're missing."
A woman: "This is why you're not Praying at all." (unintelligible)
You just try reading and you'll see what it is.
A woman: It's such a big deal. Very educated people are doing it. Never read it with the meaning. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Parivash: They are afraid of their changing the meaning. (unintelligible) A woman: Yeah, they've been told that it is different.
Parivash: If you don't understand, you're not allowed. Dr. Khalifa: It's just an excuse.
A woman: If I read it, I just read it in Arabic.
Dr. Khalifa: It's just an excuse.
Dr. Khalifa: Again, the fellow that I argued with for two or three hours here,
at the end of which I discovered he never read the Quran.
And he has a degree in management.
So, how many textbooks did he read to get a degree in management?
He memorized and took tests.
It's just an excuse to say that.
When they say they don't read the Quran, it's because they don't care. Yes.
They don't believe.
A man: Rashad, I think maybe part of it is some of the mullahs.
A man: They keep their jobs for themselves. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: They always try to make the Quran like it's not accessible.
A man: It's very hard to understand. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Exactly.
A man: "You have to come to me so I tell you what it means." Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: "And even in all of our lives, we never can understand the Quran."
A man: And especially with the type of translation that they have. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: If you read the Quran, you can understand it more than if you read the Arabic because Arabic is not our language.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. Is Naghmeh here?
A woman: No. I think she...
Dr. Khalifa: Good. Then I can say... See, the lawyers, for example, create a jargon.
Life is very simple and the issues before the court are very simple.
But the lawyers create such a jargon to monopolize the jobs, you know.
This is really a very valid principle.
And the same with the chemists.
Is Dr. Sabahi here?
The chemists create, I'm one of them, who create a certain jargon to monopolize the...
We make very simple things very complicated. Because this is how we keep our jobs.
The doctors do the same thing.
In fact, they don't even write legibly, so you don't read the writing.
This is why they keep a secret code between them and the pharmacist.
A man: It's the same thing with the Hadith and the book of Hadith. Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
A man: I read some of it and I said "who can understand and remember this? This is
"twenty-eight things about how to just make a glass of water."
Honestly, twenty-eight only to...
If they give you the glass of water, you have to hold it in two hands and you have to go up in one... Dr. Khalifa: Yes
A man: It's a lot of detail and so they make it. It's like a (unintelligible).
It's so complicated. At the end of the day, you have no choice. Just go to the tax office so you can do it. You know, it's not straightforward, (unintelligible) yourself.
I think if they say "okay, (unintelligible) Quran and read Quran, then all these women have to go and work.
and they will be making more money.
Dr. Khalifa: This is actually a funny incident.
I told it to some of you. Bear with me.
A man: Isn't that you tried to tell a Mullah...
Dr. Khalifa: I took an American friend with me to Egypt who was a new Muslim.
And we were in my hometown and the representative in the parliament for my section happens to be a fanatic Sunni.
And he met us and was very impressed by this new Muslim. And he invited him to a Coke.
Ok. So, he said "let's have a Coke." So, he opened a bottle of Coke
and he offered it to Dale. That was my friend's name.
So, Dale reaches for the bottle of Coke and this member of parliament, he pulls it back.
And then, he offers it again. So, Dale reaches for it and he pulls it back.
So, Dale whispered to me "What's going on here?"
"What happened?" I said "just watch."
So, he reaches for the Coke bottle and the member of parliament pulls the bottle away.
And then, he offers it to him again.
I said "when you're reaching with your left hand."
It turns out this is true.
So, he reached with his right hand and the member of parliament said "now, we are talking."
And he gave him the Coke. But there are so many funny things that...
It turns out to be a rule.
They make up this difficult rule.
If the guy has only left hand...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: There's a rule about how to go to bathroom
A man: (unintelligible) say (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh my gosh, yes.
A man: "We shouldn't say or...."
Dr. Khalifa: This is the rules of going to the bathroom.
Dr. Khalifa: Are you saying the rules of going to the bathroom? A man: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: This is just one of the... "You have to go with the left foot" for instance and so on.
"When you see your weight, the weight of body has to be on the left foot."
A man: There is a Hadith. I read it.
A man: It says "the sun, the moon, and the wind (unintelligible), too."
A man: But eventually, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Barbara would like this statement. What if he had X-flags the night before?
A man: If the guy really gotta go, there's a rule.
Dr. Khalifa: You forget all the rules.
A man: The rules are in your name.
A man: The rules...
A man: Is there not a rule how to cut your nails? Dr. Khalifa: Yes, oh my gosh. They have...
A man: Edip will destroy it.
Dr. Khalifa: Lisa, how did you cut your nails today?
A man: (unintelligible). Now first of all, we must try from our...
Dr. Khalifa: Listen to her.
A man: Which finger is the most vulnerable finger?
A man: And you think it must be this finger because it shows God is one.
A man: And then, because it's first study, but the second one is finger.
A man: And it must be on the right side. Ok.
A man: And you go on the right side, finish this, and you come to... There is no finger on this side.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't be too sure.
Go ahead.
Edip: You go through this (unintelligible) from here or from here? It's tight.
Edip: It's close to this, but it's right. It's left or it's right. And how can we do? If you turn
Edip: in this way, and then you have to go in this way. But if you turn in this way, you have to go in this way.
Edip: Which way is the natural? This way or this way?
Dr. Khalifa: And this is only the first page.
Edip: And then, after a very long discussion, we read Imam Ghazali, one of the biggest Ulemas. And he has a lot of books.
Edip: And then, he decides we have to put our hands in this way and go on, finish this.
Now, we have one red. This is the poorest finger.
Edip: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The least honorable.
Edip: Yes.
A woman: Well, which one is that?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: How else will Satan divert us from reading the Quran?
A man: How many people actually believe in this?
Dr. Khalifa: More than you think.
Dr. Khalifa: My father was one of them.
Dr. Khalifa: I never understood why he was doing this system. Now, I know.
Feroz: They're building houses now I had in Pakistan where the bathroom plan say, you know, the washroom should not be facing the Ka‘bah.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah. Absolutely. This is what Dr. Hay was talking about.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) don't say, we are not supposed to say (unintelligible) towards you.
A man: So, imagine there are times that we cannot find any direction...
Dr. Khalifa: Don't build in that place.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's go to another verse.
Boy, Satan is having fun with the disbelievers.
Number 31 says,
[30:31] You shall submit to GOD, reverence Him, observe the Contact Prayers (Salat), and do not be among the idol worshipers.
[30:32] Do not be among those who divide their religion into sects; each party rejoicing with what they have.
We had a fellow come from the Sunni mosque here.
And he told Edip he's getting sick and tired of all the fighting that's going on there.
Ok. I mean, here we are, we're reading the Quran, we all agree on a certain principle in here.
But over there, they have different sects.
And if you, if you favor one sect and not the other one, they have fights.
Dr. Khalifa: What did he tell you?
Edip: All he said was "I have (unintelligible). They hate each other there. It's not (unintelligible)."
Dr. Khalifa: It's always like that.
Dr. Khalifa: Because they do not follow this commandment.
[30:32] Do not be among those who divide their religion into sects; each party rejoicing with what they have.
See, if you looked at us 15 years ago, this fellow would be my enemy. I'll be his enemy. Because he'll be a Shia, I'll be a Sunni.
And this will be... But look, now we're sitting one, united, loving each other.
A man: Rashad, even among the Shias, I don't know if you know or not, but (unintelligible) it's like when they do the Namaz.
A man: The person who leads the Namaz doesn't mean that he is the most knowledgeable or not.
A man: Everybody... But in Shia, you go to Imam Reza, for instance, such and such Imam or whatever,
A man: and there are different groups. And they just know he is better or so you...
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is also true with the Sunnis.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: Because of... So, you see several groups.
A man: They are doing it at the same time, but some people go behind people, some people go right side, and one more (unintelligible) religion.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, it has to be the oldest man and the most knowledgeable.
And I remember we had a 90-year-old man that was a Mullah.
I used to pray Fajr in the patron saint of my hometown, in the mosque.
And quite often we'll go wake him up from Sujud.
We'll make him Sujud.
He never, he never gets up, you know.
We used to say "Hey, Mawlana."
And literally...Wait, wait a minute. When he died, I swear, when he died, President Sadat made a tomb for him.
And people go now and they worship at his tomb, this particular man.
His name was Sheikh Hijab.
Boy, I dreaded every time I go and saw him because it took one hour to pray Fajr.
Half of them Sujud. No, three quarters Sujud.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Really. Yes.
He was very, very old.
It has to be... There's a system in Sunnis.
I guess Abdul Hayy thought that since we do it here, this way, we all take turns. It doesn't matter who's leading.
This is the Sunni system. It is not.
The Sunni system and apparently also the Shia system,
there is priorities for leading the prayer.
A man: One of them is (unintelligible) handicapped.
Dr. Khalifa: Should not be handicapped? A man: Handicapped.
Dr. Khalifa: I wish I knew that then.
A man: Tunnels Beach.
Dr. Khalifa: Capistrano Beach?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, faster.
Dr. Khalifa: They have to ask, they have to ask you "are you a bastard?"
Dr. Khalifa: I'm sure these are written in a book, as to the priorities, the conditions of leading the Prayer.
Dr. Khalifa: What else?
A man: Edip, what about if they're all bastards?
Dr. Khalifa: I know they have to be, it has to be the oldest one and most knowledgeable, and so on. There's a set of priorities.
Dr. Khalifa: Huh?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They do. Actually, they say "I am more worthy of leading a Prayer than you. I have a PhD from the Azhar University."
And the other will say "I have the PhD plus this and that. I'm also seven days older than you."
Really.
Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Humbly.
Dr. Khalifa: The Ahmadi Mullah in Canada said "I will humbly lead the prayer." Ismail Barakat said "you will humbly sit down right there."
He said it, he said it very angrily.
He's supposed to be here, by the way.
Ismail, Ismail Barakat.
Dr. Khalifa: Saeed Talari will be here on Thursday, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: IN SHAA ALLAH.